Finding Aid for the Dorothy Bethurum Loomis Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Dorothy Bethurum Loomis Papers
circa 1918-1983
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0266
4.05 linear_feet
Biographical Sketch
Dorothy Bethurum Loomis of Franklin, Tennessee was a Vanderbilt Alumna, Bachelor of Arts 1919 and Master of Arts 1922. She went on to obtain her doctorate from Yale University in 1930 and also studied at Oxford as a Fulbright Fellow. While at Vanderbilt, Loomis was a Founder's Medalist, editor of the Commodore, president of the Scribblers, vice-president of the YWCA, on the Hustler staff, permanent class secretary, a member of the Kappa Alpha Theta sorority, and Phi Beta Kappa student president. After finishing her education, she taught at Randolph Macon Women's College and at Lawrence College. In 1937 Loomis was a Guggenheim Fellow in England. By 1940, she accepted a position as Professor of English and head of the department at Connecticut College for Women. In 1946 she served as chairman of the English Institute. Through her professional life Loomis maintained her ties with Vanderbilt University, at times serving as a visiting professor. She was also a member of the Alumni Association Board of Directors, 1953-57. Through her research and dedicated scholarship, Loomis was an authority on the medieval and Anglo-Saxon period.
Scope and Content Note
The Dorothy Bethurum Loomis papers range from material collected at the beginning of the 20th century to those collected in the late 1980s. The first box of the collection consists of Loomis's biographical and academic materials such as personal correspondences, newspaper clippings, photographs, and handwritten notes found in her papers. Also included are her academic writings/published articles. The next box consists of teaching tools such as handouts, transparencies, and translated works. Boxes 3-5 consist of Loomis's collected papers relating to the academic scholarship of other Loomis family members, including photographs and articles by her husband Roger Sherman Loomis and his previous two wives, Laura Hibbard Loomis and Gertrude Schoepperle. Boxes 6-9 consist of a collection of articles written by other scholars on medieval studies and the Anglo-Saxon period. The series and subseries of this collection are as follows:
Biographical
Correspondence
Publications
Newspaper clippings
Photographs
Notes
Academic
Articles
Translated Works
Teaching Tools
Loomis family Academics
Roger Sherman Loomis's Images
Loomis Family Writings
Other Academics' Writings
- Series I: Biographical
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence: Incoming (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Incoming (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Incoming (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Incoming (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Incoming, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Publications
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art Bulletin, Summer, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art Bulletin, May, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, The Nine Heroes Tapestries at the Cloisters: A Picture Book (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art Bulletin, June, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - The Loomis Bulletin: The Harvest of Our Lives: the History of the First Half-Century of the Loomis Institute, March, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Milkin University Festival of Theatre Arts, November 11-23, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Memorial Services for Roger Sherman Loomis (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - The Book Club (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - The Thomas S. Jones Collection, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings
    - Newspaper Clippings:, July 6, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Photographs
    - Photographs: Unidentified, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Notes
    - Miscellaneous Notes found in Loomis Papers (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Series II: Academic
  - Articles
    - Dorothy Bethurum, "Archbishop Wulfstan's Commonplace Book", December, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Dorothy Bethurum, "The Connection of the Katherine Group with Old English Prose", October, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Dorothy Bethurum, "A Letter of Protest from the English Bishops to the Pope", undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Dorothy Bethurum, "Review: Wulfstanstudien (Karl Jost)", February, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Dorothy Bethurum, "Six Anonymous Old English Codes", October, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Dorothy Bethurum, "Stylistic Features of the Old English Laws", July, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Translated Works
    - Translation: Arnold of Villa Nora: On the Secrets of Nature (Work Copy) (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Translation: Arnold of Villa Nora: On the Secrets of Nature (Draft) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Translation: Arnoldi de Villa Nova De Secretis Nature (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Translation: De Secretis Nature, cont. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Translation: The Second Book of Gerber, of the Sum of Perfection of the Perfect Majesty, pg 134-245 (Work copy) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Translation: Second Book of Gerber, Cont. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Translation: Second Book of Gerber, Cont. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Notes for Gerber Translation (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Translation: Geberis, Summa Perfectione Magisterii (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Translation: Geberis, Summa, cont. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Translation: Geberis, Summa, cont. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Translation: Summa Geberis, (1678) pg 75-133 (Typescript) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Teaching Tools
    - Diagrams of Alchemy (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Transparencies of Chapter 3, Of the Sum of Perfection, Geber (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Overhead Projector, MS Ashmole (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Overhead Projector, MS Ashmole, 1384, pg 91-93 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Artis auniferal quam Chemiann vocant, volumina duo Basel, 1610, pg 245-254 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Hand out for Alchemy Lecture, Sept 18, 1980, Edgar H. Duncan (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Series III: Loomis Family Academics
  - Roger Sherman Loomis Images
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, Prose Lancelot Manuscript, "The First Kiss of Lancelot and Guinevere," and "Lancelot at the Tomb of Galehaut", undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis Purchased Images (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis Purchased Images (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis Purchased Images (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, A Mirror of Chaucer's World: Images 1-8 (missing image 7) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, A Mirror of Chaucer's World: Images 12-19 (missing images 9, 10, 11, 13, 17) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, A Mirror of Chaucer's World: Images 21-31 (missing images 20, 22, 25, 28) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, A Mirror of Chaucer's World: Images 32-54 (missing images 40, 42-52) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, A Mirror of Chaucer's World: Images 55-82 (missing images 56-62, 64-66, 68-73, 77) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, A Mirror of Chaucer's World: Images 83-92 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, A Mirror of Chaucer's World: Images 93-102 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, A Mirror of Chaucer's World: Images 106-129 (missing images 103-105, 107, 109, 113-117, 119, 120, 123-127) (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, A Mirror of Chaucer's World: Images 133-179 (missing images 130-132, 137-142, 144-147, 149-176) (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis Miscellaneous Images (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis Miscellaneous Images (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis Miscellaneous Images (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis Miscellaneous Images (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis Miscellaneous Images (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis Miscellaneous Images (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis Miscellaneous Images (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis Miscellaneous Images (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis Miscellaneous Images (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis Miscellaneous Images (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Loomis Family Writings
    - Clara D. Loomis, "The Art of the Rate Chinese Print", undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Clara D. Loomis, "A Study of Chinese and Japanese Colour Prints", undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Laura A. Hibbard, "The Books of Sir Simon de Burley, 1387", June, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Laura Hibbard Loomis, "Chaucer and the Breton Lays of the Auchinleck MS", April, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Laura Hibbard Loomis, "L'oriflamme de France et le cri ‘Munjoie' au XII Siecle" (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Laura Hibbard Loomis, "The Oriflamme of France and the War-Cry ‘Monjoie' in the 12th Century" (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Laura Hibbard Loomis, "Review: Biography of a War Novel: Zola's ‘La Debacle,'", December, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "Anglo-Norman Literature and Its Background (M. Dominica Legge)", 1964 (3 copies) (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "The Chaldean Stones in the Lapidary of Alfonso X", undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "Chivalric and Dramatic Imitations of Arthurian Romance" (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "The Concept of Joseph of Arimathea in ‘Perlesvaus,'", 1970 (2 copies) (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "A Defense of Naturalism", undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "Did Gawain, Perceval, and Arthur Hail from Scotland?", undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - D. D. R. Owen and R. S. Loomis, "Discussion: The Development of Arthurian Romance", January, 1965 (2 copies) (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "Fundamental Facts about Arthurian Origins", 1966 (3 copies) (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "The Heraldry of Hector or Confusion Worse Confounded", January, 1967 (2 copies) (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "How They Captured Castles with Roses", October, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "König Arthur Und Die Antipoden", 1970 (2 copies) (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "A Medieval Ivory Casket", December, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "Modena, Bari, and Hades" (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "Morgain La Fée in Oral Tradition" (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "Objections to the Celtic Origin of the ‘Matiere de Bretagne,'", undated (2 copies) (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "The Origin and Date of the Bayeux Embroidery", undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "The Pas Saladin in Art and Heraldry" (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "Pioneers in Arthurian Scholarship", undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "Review: Die Frühen Darstellungen Des Arthurstoffes (W. F. Schirmer)", October, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "Review: The Grail and its Mysteries (Leonardo Olschki)", undated (2 copies) (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "Review: King Arthur's Avalon: The Story of Glastonbury (G. Ashe)", January, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "Review: The Romance of the Grail (Fanni Bogdanow)", September, 1967 (2 copies) (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - R. S. Loomis, "Scotland and the Arthurian Legend" (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "Some Additional Sources of Perlesv Aus", undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Roger Sherman Loomis, "The Strange History of Caradoc of Vannes", undated (4 copies) (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Gertrude Schoepperle (Mrs. Roger Sherman Loomis), "The Old French Lai de Nabaret" (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Clara D. Loomis's Research Images
    - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings of Clara D. Loomis (Box 5, Folder 34.)
    - Images for Clara D. Loomis, "The Art of Rare Chinese Print", undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Miscellaneous Images of Clara D. Loomis (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Series IV Other Academics' Writings
  - Robert W. Ackerman, "The Debate of the Body and the Soul and Parochial Christianity", October, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Robert W. Ackerman, "Sir Frederic Madden and the Study of Medieval Literature" (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - John M. Aden, "Bethel's Sermon and Pope's Exemplum: Towards a Critique", Summer, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Pauline Aiken, "Vincent of Beauvais and Chaucer's Monk's Tale", January, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Robert J. Allen, "A Recurring Motif in Chaucer's House of Fame", July, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Ruth M. Ames, "The Source and Significance of 'The Jew and The Pagan,'", undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Albert C. Baugh, "The Middle English Romance: Some Questions of Creation, Presentation, and Preservation", January, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Albert C. Baugh, "The End-Products of Research", January, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Albert C. Baugh, "Improvisation in the Middle English Romance", June, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - A. C. Baugh, "Review: Die Mittelenglischen Romanzen Des 13, Und 14. Jahrhunderts (D. Mehl)", January, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Albert C. Baugh, "Review: Proverbs, Sentences, and Proverbial Phrases from English Writing Mainly Before 1500 (Barlett Jere Whiting)", October, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Albert C. Baugh, "Review: A Reading of the Canterbury Tales (B. F. Huppe)", undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Albert C. Baugh, "Review: The Art of the Canterbury Tales (P. G. Ruggiers)", undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Albert C. Baugh, "Review: The Legends of King Richard I, Coeur de Lion: A Study of Sources and Variations to the Year 1600 (B. B. Broughton)", April, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Albert C. Baugh, "Chaucer's Serjeant of the Law and the Year Books" (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Albert C. Baugh, "Convention and Individuality in the Middle English Romance" (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Albert C. Baugh, "Fifty Years of Chaucer Scholarship", October, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Paul E. Beichner, "The Grain of Paradise", April, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Paul E. Beichner, "Daun Piers, Monk and Business Administrator", October, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - H. S. Bennett, "Printers, Authors, and Readers, 1475-1557" (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Morton W. Bloomfield, "The Origin of the Concept of the Seven Cardinal Sins", April, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Morton W. Bloomfield, "Symbolism in Medieval Literature", November, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Harry Bober, "Andre Beauneveu and Mehun-sur-ye'vre", October, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Lester K. Born, "Ovid and Allegory", October, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Haldeen Braddy, "The Parlement of Foules: A New Proposal" (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Haldeen Braddy, "Three Chaucer Notes" (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Haldeen Braddy, "Froissart's Account of Chaucer's Embassy in 1377", January, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Haldeen Braddy, "New Documentary Evidence Concerning Chaucer's Mission to Lombardy", December 1933 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Leicester Bradner, "The Theme of Privanza in Spanish and English Drama, 1590-1625" (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Bertrand H. Bronson, "Afterthoughts on the Merchant's Tale", October, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Bertrand H. Bronson, "In Appreciation of Chaucer's Parlement of Foules" (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Beatrice Daw Brown, Marlowe, Faustus and Simon Magus", March, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Carleton Brown, "Author's Revision in the Canterbury Tales", March, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Carleton Brown, "Review: The Text of the Canterbury Tales (John M Manly and Edith Rickert)", December, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Carleton Brown, "Three Notes on the Text of The Canterbury Tales", March, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Carleton Brown, "Chaucer's Wreched Engendring", December, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Oscar Cargill and Margaret Schlauch, "The Pearl and its Jeweler" (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Paul M. Clogan, "Chaucer and the Thebaid Scholia", October, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - John Daniel Cooke, "Euhemerism: A Mediaeval Interpretation of Classical Paganism" (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Mrs. Trenchard Cox, "The Twelfth-Century Design Sources of the Worcester Cathedral Misericords", November, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - G. G. Coulton, "The Reformation Again", January, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Ruth Crosby, "Oral Delivery in the Middle Ages" (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Charles Donahue, "The Valkyries and the Irish War-Goddesses", March, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - E. Talbot Donaldson, "The Ending in Chaucer's Troilus" (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - E. Talbot Donaldson, "Malory and the Stanzaic Le Morte Arthur", July, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - E. Talbot Donaldson, "Mss R and F in the B-Tradition of Piers Plowman", September, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - E. Talbot Donaldson, "'Piers Plowman' Textual Comparison and the Question of Authorship" (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - E. T. Donaldson, "The Texts of Piers Plowman: Scribes and Poets", May, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - E. Talbot Donaldson, "Venus and the Mother of Romulus: the Parliament of Fowls and the Pervigilium Veneris", undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Peter Dronke, "Guillaume IX and Courtoisie" (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Peter Dronke, "New Approaches to the School of Chartres" (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Edgar H. Duncan, "'Bear on Hand' in The Wife of Bath's Prologue,'" (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Edgar H. Duncan, "Chaucer's 'Wife of Bath's Prologue,' Lines 193-828 and Geoffrey of Vinsauf's Documentum", February, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Edgar H. Duncan, "The Literature of Alchemy and Chaucer's Canon's Yeoman's Tale: Framework, Theme, and Characters", October, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Harvey Eagleson, "Costume in the Middle English Metrical Romances," Coolidge Otis Chapman, "Authorship of the 'Pearl,'" Oscar Cargill, "The Date of the A-text of 'Piers Ploughman,'" Howard William Troyer, "Who is Piers Plowman?" (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Oliver Farrar Emerson, "More Notes on Pearl", December, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Oliver Farrar Emerson, "Middle English Clannesse", undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Robert M. Estrich, "Chaucer's Prologue to the Legend of Good Women and Machaut's Le Jugement Dou Roy De Navarre", January, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Robert M. Estrich, "Chaucer's Maturing Art in the Prologues to the Legend of Good Women", July, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - W. H. French, "Medieval Chess and the Book of the Duchess", April, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Wilbur Gaffney, "The Allegory of the Christ-Knight in Piers Plowman" (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Alan Gaylord, "Chaucer's Squire and the Glorious Campaign" (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Alan T. Gaylord, "The Unconquered Tale of the Prioress" (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - G. E. Gerould, "Arthurian Romance and the Modena Relief", October, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Marie P. Hamilton, "Bernard the Monk: Postscript", March, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Marie P. Hamilton, "The Dramatic Stability of 'The Man of Law's Tale,'" (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Marie Padgett Hamilton, "The Meaning of the Middle English Pearl", September, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Marie P. Hamilton, "Notes on Pearl", April, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Francoise Henry, "Early Christian Irish Art" (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Millett Henshaw, "The Date of the Composition of Andreas Capellanus's De Amore" (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Arthur W. Hoffman, "Chaucer's Prologue to Pilgrimage: the Two Voices", March, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Donald R. Howard, "Chaucer the Man", September, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Donald R. Howard, "The Conclusion of the Marriage Group Chaucer and the Human Condition", May, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Donald R. Howard, "Review: Fruyt and Chaf: Studies in Chaucer's Allegories (Bernard F. Huppe and D. W. Robertson, Jr.)", July, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Donald R. Howard, "Structure and Symmetry in Sir Gawain", July, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - James Root Hulbert, "The Source of St. Erkenwald and The Trental of Gregory", January, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - James Root Hulbert, "The 'West Midland' of the Romances", August, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Robert M. Jordan, "The Narrator in Chaucer's Troilus", December, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - R. E. Kaske, "An Aube in the Reeve's Tale", September, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - R. E. Kaske, "The Canticum Canticorum in the Miller's Tale", July, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - R. E. Kaske, "Eve's 'Leaps' in the Ancrene Riwle", undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - R. E. Kaske, "Gigas The Giant in Piers Plowman", April, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - R. E. Kaske, "The Knight's Interruption of the Monk's Tale", December, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - R. E. Kaske, "Langland's Walnut-Simile", October, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - R. E. Kaske, "The Summoner's Garleek, Oynons, and eek Lekes", June 1959 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - R. E. Kaske, "Two Cruxes in 'Pearl': 596 and 609-10" (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Alfred Kellogg, "Comic Scriptural Allusions in Beroul's 'Tristran,'", June 1, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Alfred L. Kellogg, "Langland and Two Scriptural Texts" (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Alfred L. Kellogg, "Susannah and the Merchant's Tale", April, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - A. L. Kellogg and Ernest W. Talbert, "The Wyclifite Pater Noster and Ten Commandments, with Special Reference to English MSS .85 and 90 in the John Rylands Library", March, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Alfred Allan Kern, "The Ancestry of Chaucer" (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - John Koch, "Chaucer's 'Minor Poems,'" (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - John Koch, "Chaucer's Parlement of Foules", 1904 (German) (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - James R. Kreuzer, "The Dreamer in the Book of the Duchess", June, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Charlton Laird, "A Fourteenth Century Scribe", December, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - John Livingston Lowes, "Chaucer and the Ovide moralisé" (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - John Livingston Lowes, "Chaucer's Boethius and Jean De Meun", eOctober-December, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - John Livingston Lowes, "The Two Prologues to the Legend of Good Women: A New Test", undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - R. M. Lumiansky, "The Bereaved Narrator in Chaucer's The Book of the Duchess" (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Francis P. Magoun, Jr., "Scottish History in the 'Lay of Gurun,'" (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Kemp Malone, "Review: Middle English Dictionary (Hans Kurath)" (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - John M. Manly, "Chaucer's Mission to Lombardy", April, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Irene Pettit McKeehan, "Guillaume de Palerne: A Medieval 'Best Seller,'", undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Leland Miles, "Persecution and the Dialogue of Comfort: a Fresh Look at the Charges Against Thomas More", November 1965 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Henry Allen Moe, "'The Vision of Piers the Plowman' and the Law of Foundations", August, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - A. L. Moir, "The World Map in Hereford Cathedral," Malcolm Letts, "The Pictures in the Hereford Mappa Mundi", January, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Arthur K. Moore, "Chaucer's Use of Lyric as an Ornament of Style", Winter, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Dana Carleton Munro, "The Western Attitude Toward Islam During the Period of the Crusades" (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Charles Muscatine, "Locus of Action in Medieval Narrative", August, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - H. Newstead, "Arthurian and Carolingian Legends", undated (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Helaine Newstead, "The Equivocal Oath in the Tristan Legend", undated (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Helaine Newstead, "The Harp and the Rote", May, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Helaine Newstead, "Isolt of the White Hands and Tristan's Marriage", November, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - H. Newstead, "Legends, Medieval", undated (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Helaine Newstead, "Recent Perspectives on Arthurian Literature" (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Helaine Newstead, "Review: Anglo-Norman Literature and its Background (Dominica Legge)", January, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Helaine Newstead, "Review: Art and Tradition in Sir Gawain and the Green Knight," Lionel J. Friedman, "Reivew: Pedro Antonio de Alarcon, El Sombrero de tres picos," Helaine Newstead, "Review: The Breton Lays in Middle English", February, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 60)